[Music]
how do you feel about the recent
Father's Day celebration over the
weekend happy that you were able to
spend more time with your family sad
because there are family members that
are no longer there how do you feel
about the state of the nation okay I
won't go there that's too political for
me okay how do you feel about insurance
I know right actually when I ask that
same question to myself I don't know how
to feel about insurance because for the
longest time when you say insurance it's
it's not really the sexiest thing that
you can talk about so at the FWD our
goal is really we are working hard to
change the way people feel about
insurance so there are really a lot of
perceptions misconceptions about
insurance in general right so both true
and there are a lot of them are false as
well so when I joined the industry like
what I said five years ago so some of
the things that I actually heard from
friends from colleagues from from people
in general is that they said when you
talk about insurance especially the
policy in particular in Filipino we have
this term nosebleed right so no suite it
means it's difficult to comprehend it
means the terms and conditions in the
policy packs are kinda legalese
it's very jargon I also heard that when
you say insurance
it's about very how do you call it
aggressive salespeople were in they will
really go follow you and at the end you
will just tell them that you already
have insurance when in fact we don't
have yet just to actually move away from
them we also see some also in the policy
in the policy paper in the document some
disclaimers or even they say they will
cover you but they don't so there are a
lot of those perceptions they also told
me that okay when you buy insurance you
see the interaction with the financial
advice or even with the company several
times but then when you started becoming
the client the interaction lessened
so they also told me that when you say
when you talk about insurance it's not
innovative enough compared to the other
industry mind you I came from
advertising so it's really a totally
different world apart they also said
that insurance is for people with money
and also for those who are old people so
there are really a lot of misconceptions
perception some of them may be true
because it's it's it's been there for
years right so at FWD our goal is really
to challenge and change this conceptions
of the fear factor because we believe
that insurance should be a source of
optimism and that the role of the
company and the insurance firm in
general is to make sure that people live
life to the fullest and also to remove
their worries aways yeah so as you can
see if you've been exposed to some of
our let's say communication pieces when
you say FWD it has that youthful vibe it
also has that a very positive spin to
celebrate living because that's the the
DNA of the brand so now okay let's just
talk about just a bit of FWD because we
know were a very new player we started
our journey in the Philippines in q4 of
2014 so again when we started the name
its FWD unfortunately we don't say it
forward I know but there's a legal thing
behind that some people also said okay
FWD I know that that's four-wheel-drive
I said no the FWD and then the last one
they said I was in the mall and then
they said okay you're from FWD I have a
parking for you
so yeah FWD PWD so anyway I said FWD
doesn't stand for anything yeah it's a
fresh and innovative approach to
insurance so who we are rep a nation in
shooter built in the head office in Hong
Kong so we're now in nine markets so
only after four in in Hong Kong we
started in 2015 with acquisition of ing
actually digital is at the core of our
existence how do we push the envelope
we've invested 50 million dollars in
ensuring that 60% of our IT budget is
based on allocated and digitalization so
that's how important it is to us from
the inception in 2014 we right now for
right now one of the top 10 so from
start up to top 10 we're in that space
where
fastest highest capitalized in the in
the market today aside from that what
I'm proud of is that we are 24/7 when
you talk about insurance we don't really
think of calling them 24/7 but really
people really do talk to us and they
also chat to us so we are the first
insurer who operated our customer
engagement center 24/7 not just on voice
but also on shaft and aside from that we
also pioneered a very bold proposition
where and we financially protect people
who are hit by acts of terror or sort of
terrorism
so that's never heard of so nobody wants
to cover it we covered it and we're also
the first to cover extreme sports but I
know it's kind of difficult to digest
that especially for the younger
generation because for them insurance
it's like it has like that legacy type
of background so for example we created
this game we call it Ernie Ernie is it's
a web-based so it's it's it's an
education game right and it just tells
you that okay it expenses to earnings
we're not telling you remind you to give
up your daily coffee if you want to go
ahead okay have your coffee because
that's impossible to just give up but we
are just telling telling you right if
you go to Starbucks three times a week
just remove one you go two times what is
the impact of that one Frappuccino
versus 150 pesos to your long-term
savings that you can do that you can use
for investment and protection so that's
where the game was used so whenever we
do let's say our Roadshow we don't
actually talk there and give out flyers
because they're so passe this for real
insurance hardcore right but for us we
just give them an option that hey guys
play the game have a look and then they
will realistically just feel that okay
this is maybe something for me
so FWD is a cost or my led company so CX
is if the shuttle is at the core of our
existence
what more customer experience we really
value what the customers tell us because
gone are the days that relationship of
insurance companies where the people is
just like three times in two decades you
talk to them when you're precious
you talk
them when you renew if it's not water in
you well and you talk to them when you
claim so sometimes or most of the time
when you do the claim you're not there
anymore so the three interactions become
two that's why it's very important that
you have 24/7 and this is also important
to us because the let's say the way we
work in the Philippines it's not just
8:05 anymore we have a lot of the BPO
sectors wherein it's 24/7 people wanted
to talk to you at the most crazy hours
like 1:00 a.m. but it doesn't matter we
are there yeah so we have distorted with
the 24/7 operations the first in late
2017 and then in early 2018 we started
the chat so we were thinking at that
time if you have the voice Y chat but
then we observe the customer behavior
we're in people sometimes don't want to
talk to a voice or to a human being
we're so used to instant messaging viber
that sometimes we'll just be sitting
beside each other you and you still send
viber to each other right that's the
reason we have live chat when you don't
want to hear a voice and you can always
detach yourself then you do the chat and
it proved to be very essential for us
but aside from that as well if you're in
our customers we have what we call tap
tap is an app it's a one stop insurance
app wherein our policyholders can manage
report folio can pay their premium can
change their data can get can see
projections of their investment and can
also look at content again
especially for our industry in the world
of omni-channel experiences right again
we don't want especially for insurance
we don't want only three interactions
you want to be there in all in all the
stages of your life we wanted to be in
your micro moments and the only way for
us to do that is to be part of the
omni-channel experience where and we
provide if you look at our social media
sites the content is very bite-sized
it's very luminous so not your usual
highfalutin legalese terminologies we
also employ I think some a lot of the
media people friends we will say
look-alike modeling
Reiki and we look at our segments of the
market
if the performance of conversion is
there and then you basically copy it and
then load it up again so there are a lot
of things that we're doing at the
background again the goal of the company
is to change the way people feel about
insurance the more people who the more
people feel comfortable and understand
what the mission really is for the
insurance industry in general the more
people that will get protected so
hopefully that 7.4% of penetration rate
or those who have life insurance in
general will be much higher in the next
few years
[Music]